[MUSIC PLAYING]
Hi, I'm registered
dietitian nutritionist,
Sara Haas with the Academy
of Nutrition and Dietetics.
Onions are a stable in nearly
every cultural cuisine.
But this aromatic
superstar has a knack
for making the cook cry.
That's because when
you cut an onion,
it releases gases into the air
that can irritate our eyes.
Here are some tricks on how
to cut an onion without tears.
You can open a nearby
window, light a candle,
or wear protective eye wear.
Another easy tip
is to keep the cut
side of onion flat
against the board
to help keep it from
releasing mist into the air
while you're working with it.
There are also
special kitchen tools
designed for chopping onions
and containing the oils.
No matter which
method you choose,
always be sure to wash your
hands in hot, soapy water
to prevent the oil from
getting on your eyes and face.
And that's how you cut
an onion without tears.
For more tips and information,
be sure to visit eatright.org.
[MUSIC PLAYING]