JENNIFER ISERLOH: Asparagus is
a cleansing spring vegetable
that can make a tasty
side dish or star
in your favorite main dish.
It's also great for
digestive health.
Asparagus is prebiotic, meaning
it feeds the helpful bacteria
that live in your gut.
These good bacteria are
responsible for everything
from signaling
your immune system
and keeping digestion in check,
to producing vital B vitamins.
When shopping for
asparagus, look
for spears that are free
of blemishes and dry spots,
and look for tips that
are closed and firm.
Use asparagus promptly--
it can spoil quickly.
Miso asparagus is
an easy side dish
that can also be
served as a main dish
when served over salad
or with sliced chicken.
Miso is a paste made
from fermented soybeans.
Find it at health and
Asian food stores.
Start by trimming off the
tough ends of the asparagus.
Next, warm the sesame oil in a
large skillet over medium heat.
Add the asparagus and cook four
to five minutes, turning often
until the asparagus
softens and browns.
Place one tablespoon of
miso paste in a large bowl.
Next, whisk together ginger,
garlic, and two tablespoons
of warm water.
Then just pour over
the cooked asparagus,
sprinkle with sesame
seeds, and enjoy.
[MUSIC PLAYING]