[MUSIC PLAYING]
MATT: We were having a good
time, waiting for the big day.
When they told us
that she had listeria,
we had no idea what it
was, absolutely no clue.
ERIN: Matt and I wanted a child.
We gave ourselves a
three-month window.
And lo and behold,
we got pregnant.
At my baby shower,
we had just a handful
of girlfriends, presents,
cake, fruit, vegetables,
and the lovely cheese tray.
MATT: It started,
I think, on Monday.
By Wednesday, she had a fever.
It was 102.4.
Doctor said, take her
to the emergency room.
They checked the baby.
Allison was in distress.
Her heartbeat was dropping.
ERIN: And that's when
they said, you're
going to have a baby tonight.
And I was like,
I'm only 33 weeks.
You have this
frail little being,
and she's got eight tubes
running in and out of her.
ERIN: She was considered septic.
They had to do rounds of massive
antibiotics 24 hours a day.
It wasn't until
afterwards I learned--
you stay away from your deli
meats, your soft cheeses.
I didn't know that it could
harbor pathogens like listeria.
Allison today is headstrong,
feisty, a spitfire,
and the light of my life.
She's strong.
And that's what I love.
Looking at me when
I was in the NICU,
you see tubes and
monitors and everything.
I feel lucky that I am alive.
Listeria caused prematurity.
It runs its own game.
It's harder for me
to learn, but I'm
catching up to the other kids.
MATT: Today she's very
much a normal teenager.
And if you can't play
softball, she's miserable.
[CHEERING]
Food safety, for me, is pay
attention to your recalls,
first and foremost.
Pay attention to your
cooking temperature,
when it comes to your
poultry, steak, hamburger.
We check everything we buy.
C We make sure it's in date.
ALLISON: Every time we get
new vegetables and things,
mom washes them immediately.
ERIN: For a pregnant mom,
pay attention to the doctor's
list of foods to stay away from.
But not everybody
understands to stay away
from your deli meats,
unpasteurized cheese,
and soft cheese.
Being a food-borne
illness survivor,
knowing that my
child almost died,
you don't take a
day for granted.
[MUSIC PLAYING]