[MUSIC PLAYING]
Crohn's disease triggers
vary from person to person.
However, the following
are frequently
cited causes of
aggravated inflammation.
Emotional stress, large meals,
nonsteroidal anti-inflammatory
drugs, greasy foods,
high-fiber diets
including fresh fruits and
greens, dairy products,
foods that cause gas such
as broccoli, popcorn,
and beans, coffee, soda,
and alcohol, and hot spices.
Smoking may also make
Crohn's symptoms more severe.
And smokers may also
be more likely to need
surgery for Crohn's disease.
Learning what your
triggers are can
help you make lifestyle changes
that will help you manage
or inflammatory bowel disease.
To learn more about controlling
your Crohn's disease
or ulcerative colitis, watch
more videos in this series.